### CLARA CHUA KIAH HWII

clarachua@gmail.com • +65 9833 0668 • linkedin.com/in/chuaclara • Singaporean

### **SUMMARY**

**Versatile professional** with over 15 years of experience in developing and implementing People strategies and solutions; **Creating people insights** through various data sources and facilitating conversations between teams across the business; **Passionate about productivity** and using data and technology to make lives better.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Business Intelligence
- Data Modelling / Reporting
- Data Visualisation
- Facilitation Skills
- R, R Shiny, Tableau and Python

Stakeholder & Partner Management

#### Data Visualisation

#### **EDUCATION**

### **SINGAPORE MANAGEMENT UNIVERSITY** - Singapore

Jan 2018 - Apr 2021

Master of IT in Business (Analytics) GPA: 3.88

Key Courses: Big Data, Visual Analytics; Operations Analytics with a focus on Optimisation; Spreadsheet Modelling; Social Analytics; Internet of Things; Applied Machine Learning

# **UNIVERSITY OF NOTTINGHAM** – UK

Sep 1996 - Jul 1999

**BSc. (Hons) Economics & Econometrics** 

### **EXPERIENCE**

## CIRCLES.LIFE (LIBERTY WIRELESS PTE LTD) - Singapore

Apr 2019 - Present

Contractor (Nov 2020 – Present)

• Run quarterly performance management cycle

### People & Culture Analytics Lead (Apr 2019 – Oct 2020)

- Work with department heads to develop workforce planning process based on business strategy and budgets.
- Streamline and automate HR processes and ensure data integrity of data across various systems (HRIS, ATS, etc); Assist with data integration with partners through APIs and ETLs
- Design and develop dashboards on recruitment, manpower and performance using collated data from various sources to enable TA team and HODs to track recruiter performance, headcounts and attrition
- Designed and developed process for automating performance management system using Google Apps Script

### **Regional People Partnering Lead** (Dec 2019 – Oct 2020)

- Lead team to provide insights on employee engagement via monthly pulse check reporting
- Liaise with government agencies on talent and workforce development, ensure compliance with requirements

**BUSINESS CHINA** – Singapore

Oct 2018 - Jan 2019

**Project Consultant (Contract)** 

## NTUC LEARNINGHUB PTE LTD - Singapore

Sep 2013 - Aug 2018

#### **Principal Consultant** (Nov 2015 – Aug 2018)

- Led analytics project to build an explanatory model between honorariums and revenue and to optimize trainer honorariums using regression modelling and k-means clustering.
- Worked with tech partners, internal stakeholders and client to innovate a new training solution for a banking client. The holistic solution included curation of training courses, course registration, marketing, gamification and incentivization via mobile app, course delivery and back-end logistics. Multi-year project worth \$2.7m over 3 years.
- Facilitated 2-day design thinking led hackathon

## **General Manager, Institute of Business Excellence** (Sep 2013 – Dec 2015)

- Built business case to add on new training offerings in design thinking, and leadership skills. This included conducting feasibility studies, market forecasting and negotiating agreements with strategic partners.
- Managed the business P&L, budgeting and management reporting, resolved customer and operational issues.
- Managed termination of Disney Institute partnership, transition to new funding schemes, revision of training modules.
- Motivated team to stay engaged during difficult transition period where there was a new direction and loss of manpower at the same time.

### **CLARA CHUA**

clarachua@gmail.com • +65 9833 0668 • linkedin.com/in/chuaclara • Singaporean

### **EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)**

ERNST & YOUNG Oct 2009 - Jul 2013

### ASEAN Advisory Learning & Development Leader (Oct 2011 – Jul 2013)

- Created database of onboarding reference materials; developed process to track onboarding of new employees.
- Developed and executed L&D strategy for Advisory service line across ASEAN (8 countries) for 1,200 professionals.
- Worked with country L&D teams to ensure a consistent approach to programme delivery and manage L&D budgets.
- Developed business case for a regional learning week to deliver learning across ASEAN.

### Manager, Performance Improvement (Oct 2009 – Oct 2011)

 Managed S\$1.5m worth of projects with government agencies in competency framework development, talent management, career management, corporate governance.

ACIES PARTNERS PTE LTD Mar 2009 – Oct 2009

#### **Senior Consultant**

 Delivered S\$100,000 worth of projects in Malaysia and Singapore including projects on KPI setting, compensation and benefits review

# **MOBILE STREAMS (SINGAPORE) PTE LTD**

Aug 2007 - Feb 2009

#### **Account Director**

- Managed Singapore operations; developed partnerships and strategic alliances with content partners and vendors
- Managed and directed products and programming of music, games and downloads site for consumer

#### **CLARITY CONSULTING ASSOCIATES**

Aug 2006 - Aug 2007

### **Principal Consultant**

 Delivered projects in performance management, training (design and facilitation of 3-day Project Management Skills and 2-day Presentation Skills) in Sri Lanka with an international consumer product organisation.

#### **BRIDGE PACIFIC CONSULTING**

Nov 2004 – Aug 2006

#### **Senior Consultant**

• Secured and delivered projects in performance management for a higher education institute in Singapore resulting in better KPIs and career management tracks for teachers and administrators

MERCER HR CONSULTING Sep 2001 – Nov 2004

#### Consultant

- Worked on two large end-to-end HR transformation projects for public sector conversion into statutory boards
  involving job levelling, evaluations, competency frameworks, performance management, talent management and
  values workshops. This includes communications plans, project management and training on the new processes.
- Delivered employee opinion survey (automobile manufacturer), and work-life balance survey (public sector agency)

# MOUNTBATTEN INTERNSHIP PROGRAMME AT CENTERSEAT, LLC (NEW YORK, USA)

Jan 2000 - Jan 2001

Executive Assistant to the CEO, President & SVP Business Development | Office and Purchasing Manager

### **ADDITIONAL**

- Interests: Yoga, Cooking, Skiing, Ultimate Frisbee, Meditation, Travelling, Trivia Nights, Singing
- Technical Skills: Python, R, Tableau, Basic SQL, Big Data Architecture, JMP Pro, SAS Enterprise Guide / Enterprise Miner, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, Expert Excel skills, basic Google App scripts
- Languages: English (native), Mandarin (fluent), French (conversational)
- Awards: 3<sup>rd</sup> prize (JagaMe) at MIT HackMed Singapore, organized by IMDA and MIT (2015)
- Data Visualisation Portfolio:
  - Visualisation of air quality data [https://bit.ly/2LHRlic]
  - Visualisation and Geo-weighted Modelling of Hawker Centre Stall Rental Prices [https://bit.ly/3oWXCuj]
- Capstone Project: Geospatial Analysis of Airbnb in Singapore [https://clarachua.netlify.app/project/capstone-project/]